I'm on the way up...
途中… 途中…
I'm going up...
途中 途中…
Going up, going up...
そう考えることで
今の俺は やっと しのいでる
I can't survive unless I think
of myself as going up.
生きながらえている
That's what keeps me going.
A life with no dreams makes
me feel like I'm dead.
覇気のない
半ば眠っているような日々
ああ！ くそ…
Darn it!
That's right, I can't carry on
unless I psych myself up.
そうさ… 途中だと思わなきゃ
やってられねえ
はあ… やってられねえ
I wouldn't be able to!
Even so, what was going on?
それにしても どういうわけだ？
あの夜 俺は…
That night, I...
That night, when heaven and hell
crossed paths on board Espoir,
あの夜… すなわち
豪華客船エスポワール号で
天国と地獄が交差する
限定ジャンケンが開催された夜
the luxury liner, during the game
of Restricted Rock Paper Scissors.
67 people barely managed
to escape from a doomed fate.
かろうじて 地獄を逃れた67名
だが 彼らも
手放しで 喜べたわけではない
However, they did not
manage to celebrate.
Only 29 people cleared their debts
from society and the ship.
シャバでの借金
そして 船で借りた借金をも
きれいに精算できた者は 29名
半分にも満たない
Not even half of them!
The remaining 38...
残る38名は 借金ゼロという願いを
かなえることなく
...were unable to fulfill their
wish of eliminating their debts.
おろし損ねた荷を再び背負い
街へと戻っていった
They had to once again take up
the baggage they had laid down,
and return to the streets.
伊藤カイジ
Ito Kaiji.
According to the rules,
your external debt...
規定により
シャバの借金385万は チャラ
...of 3.85 million is eliminated.
ただし 船で生じた新たな借金
However, the new debt
you accumulated on the ship...
629万5000円
...is 6.295 million.
金利は 年18％
The annual interest is 18%.
計算の詳細は ここに書いてある
Here is the breakdown
of the calculation.
おい
Hey!
Do you think I'll repay this?
こんなもん 俺が返すと思うか？
You will.
返すさ　返させる
We'll make you pay.
次！
Next!
Messenger
あれから ４ヵ月たつのに
It's been four months,
取り立てどころか
催促の連絡一本 来ない
and they've neither contacted me
nor come to claim money.
もっとも 取り立てに来たところで
In the first place,
even if they came,
時給900円の身じゃ
金利すら払えない
I can't even pay the interest
with my hourly wage of 900 yen.
月に10万ずつ払っても
629万の元金は ほとんど減らない
Even if I gave them
100,000 a month,
it's just a small fraction of the
principle sum of 6.29 million.
まるで同じ場所を際限なく
走らされてるようなもんだ
It's as if I'm made to run on
the same spot for eternity.
これで やる気が起きるやつが
いたら マゾもいいところだ
Only a masochist would
be driven by this.
どうして 頑張れる？
How am I to be motivated?
どんなに 一生懸命
何かを築いたところで
Regardless of how hard I work, it's
just like building a sandcastle.
所詮 砂の城
ある日 ドアを開けて
取り立てが来たら それまで
The day someone walks through the
door to claim the debt, that's it.
Everything will be over.
それで 全て終わる
Darn it, darn it!
くそ… くそ…
あのおっさんさえ救わなければ
俺は プラス1000万とか
If only I hadn't saved
that old man,
I'd have been able to leave
the ship with a huge amount...
そういう大金を持って
船を降りられた
...of about 10 million.
With that amount, I may have
been able to move forward.
それだけあれば
俺は 前へ行けたかもしれない
きっかけをつかめたかもしれない
I could have grasped the
chance to change this life...
この人生を変える…
きっかけ…
The chance!
Don't slack off!
手ぇ止めてんじゃねえよ
タラタラすんな ボケが
Stop wasting time, fool.
それとな 毛！切れよ いいかげん
And please, go get a haircut!
むっ？何だ？その目は
What's with that look?
お前のそういう態度がな…
店長
That attitude of yours...
Manager!
お茶 入りました
I made you some tea!
Huh? What did you say?
何言ってんだ　今 勤務中だぞ
We're in the middle of work!
店長　大福もあるんですよ
食べません？
Manager, we have
rice cakes too.
Would you like some?
ったく ちょっとだけだぞ
Honestly...
But only for a while.
カイジさんも どうすか？
What about you, Kaiji?
Come on.
It's no use, I can't stand
this sort of atmosphere.
駄目だ　たまんねえ
こういう雰囲気 つくづく駄目だ
I just can't stand it!
こいつらみたいに
うまく取り入ることができない
I can't handle it
as well as them.
No matter where I work,
I always end up with...
結局
どこへ行っても 上司に疎まれて
ごみ出しだの窓拭きだの
損な役回りを押しつけられる
...the worst jobs, like clearing
the trash or wiping windows.
始末が悪いのは 俺自身
その方が心地いいっていうか…
I feel that being in a bad
situation has its advantages.
他人と ぬるぬる関わって
作り笑いするより
It means I needn't
put up a forced smile...
数段 楽に感じるってことだ
...or get into the good
books of others.
気が付きゃ 変人扱い
I'm always seen as
an eccentric guy.
毎度 同じパターンの繰り返し
This cycle just repeats itself.
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
えーと えーと…
お先っす
Where is it?
I'm leaving.
おい ちょっと…
Hey, wait!
Yes?
はい？
お前さ 知らないか？
Do you know where it is?
The envelope that was here...
ここにあった封筒
いえ
No.
10万 入ってたんだ
It had 100,000 in it!
悪いが
かばんの中 見せてくれないか？
Sorry, but could I
check your bag?
What?!
俺が盗んだって言うんすか？
Are you saying that I stole it?
I didn't say that.
It's just in case.
そうは言ってない　念のためだ
念のためって…
黙って見せりゃいいんだ
Just in case?
Be quiet and
let me take a look.
どう考えたって
お前が いちばん怪しい
You seem to be the most
suspicious right now.
怪しいんだ　見せろ
You're suspicious!
Let me see it!
I see. I'm suspicious,
you said?
そうすか　怪しいすか
なら 見せなきゃならないっすね
Then I'll have to
let you see it, right?
店長 棚の弁当そろそろ… えっ？
Manager, it's nearly time for
the bentos on the shelf...
I'll let you see it.
見せましょう
何？
What?
ただし ただじゃ見せない
However, I won't do it for free.
ギャンブルだ
Let's gamble on it.
Huh?
かばんを開けて 身体検査もして
その金が出てきたら
If you find the money
after checking my bag...
...and doing a body search,
I'll pay you up to a million.
俺は100万だって 店長に差し出す
In exchange...
その代わり
もし 出てこなかったら
If it isn't found, you'll have
to pay me 100,000 in return.
逆に10万 俺に払ってもらう
What?!
かまいませんよね？
I'm sure you wouldn't mind.
Suspecting someone
is a serious matter.
人を疑うってのは それくらい重い
この程度のリスクは 当たり前
It's only natural for
taking such a risk, right?
違いますか？
どうします？店長
What shall it be, Manager?
I see. So that's it, huh?
そうか… そういうことか
お前 隠したな？
You hid it, didn't you?
What...?
店のどこか あるいは
ごみ出しのとき 外に持ち出した
You hid it somewhere
in the store,
or took it out
while taking out the trash!
もう 手には持ってないから
You haven't got it with you,
that's why you threatened me!
そんな ばかな話を
吹っかけてきたんだ
そうだろうが　この ぬすっとめ！
I'm right, isn't it? You thief!
てめえ！
Darn it!
カイジさん　駄目っす
佐原
Kaiji, don't!
Sahara!
You too, Manager. Don't say
such things without proof!
店長も 確証もないのに
そんなこと言っちゃ駄目っすよ
お 俺は ただ…
I... I was just...
ぶっ殺す
カイジさん
I'll kill you!
Kaiji!
ねっ よしましょうよ
Hey, please stop this!
Let me go!
I said, let me go!
放せ　放せってんだよ
放します 放します
Alright, I'm letting go!
ここは こらえて…
ねっ？カイジさん
Don't take it personally.
Okay, Kaiji?
Don't mess with me
I'll kill him, for sure...
ふざけんな！あの野郎 絶対に…
That manager just talks big.
あの店長も… 強気は口だけで
He'll never bet a large sum
of money nor pick a fight.
大金も賭けないし
けんかも しないんすよ
あんなもんすよ
今どきの大人なんて
They're all the same;
adults these days.
Later.
ふ… ふざけるなよ
Don't mess with me.
This is war!
戦争だろうが
疑ってるうちは まだしも
それを口にしたら
Suspecting me is one thing,
but to declare it out loud...
その瞬間から 戦争だろうが！
From this moment on,
it's war!
Darn it!
くそ！
カイジさーん
Kaiji!
いや 聞いてくださいよ
あの ばか店長
Hey, please listen!
That dumb manager...
俺まで疑い始めて
ネチネチ身体検査
He started to suspect me too,
and wanted to do a body check.
やってらんないっすよ
I couldn't take it anymore!
I was so angry
that I quit on the spot!
あんまり頭来たから
スパッと辞めてやりました
辞めた？
ええ　あの ばか店長
You quit?
Yeah.
That dumb manager must have
left it somewhere and forgot.
きっと
自分が どっかに置き忘れたんすよ
I see. So you quit.
そうか 辞めたか
ってことは…
In other words...
お前か
It was you?
Huh?
店長には
金がなくなった確証があった
The manager definitely
lost the money.
でなきゃ あんな大騒ぎはしない
Or else he wouldn't
have made such a fuss.
事務所は スタッフしか入れない
No one except staff
can enter the office.
盗めたのは 俺か お前
あるいは 西尾っていう女の子
The only ones who could have
stolen it are us,
or that girl, Nisio.
だが 西尾は ずっとレジにいて
１人になる機会はなかった
But Nisio was always
at the counter,
and never had a
chance to be alone.
となると…
カ… カイジさん 冗談よしてよ
In other words...
K-Kaiji! Quit joking...
If nothing was found
from the body search,
身体検査して
何も出なかったのなら
お前は 金を盗んだ後
店のどこかに隠した
it means you hid the money
in the store after stealing it.
そして
後腐れないように 店も辞めてきた
Then you quit, so that
you wouldn't be suspected.
Wasn't that the case?
そういうことじゃないのか？
カイジさん…
Kaiji...
かーっ まいったなあ…
I give up.
Well...
しゃあない
そこまで見透かされたなら
遠慮なく…
Since I've been exposed,
I shan't hide anymore.
全く
What?!
Honestly...
どうしようかと思いましたよ
I was really at a loss.
カイジさんが
かばんから金が出たら100万払う
At that time, you said you'd
pay him a million...
なんて言いだしたときは
...if the money
was in your bag.
き… 貴様
Y-You!
どうせこれ バイト料をやつが
Anyway, this is dirty money...
...that he had taken
from our pay.
ピンはねして ためた
汚ねえ金っす
今日は おごりますよ
It's my treat today!
You...
てめえ…
俺を運び屋になんかしやがって
You used me as your scapegoat!
もう そろそろ勘弁してくださいよ
Hey, isn't it about time
you gave me a break?
謝ってるじゃないっすか
I've been apologising, haven't I?
Kaiji.
カイジさんってさ 何か
You have a different scent
from those other fellows.
そこいらの連中と
匂い違いますよね？
Huh?
危険というか
Something dangerous,
or worth a lot of money.
大金の匂いがするっていうか…
俺みたいな すかんぴん捕まえて
何 寝言ぬかしてんだ
What nonsense are you saying
to a pauper like me?
俺が言いたい大金の匂いってのは
やばいけど おいしい話
The smell of the money
I'm referring to...
...is dangerous,
but tempting.
非合法だけど 一発当てると
大金が ごそっていうやつ
It may be illegal, but one
can strike it rich in one shot.
そんな話をカイジさんは知ってる
You should know about
such things. Right, Kaiji?
違いますか？
ぶっ！ハハハ お前な
俺が そんな…
Now, what makes you think...
追われてるでしょ？
You're on the run, aren't you?
最初に入った店 そして ここでも
At the first place we
went to and here too,
カイジさんが選んだ席は
入り口が見える席でした
you chose a seat where
you can see the entrance.
And whenever someone enters,
そして 誰か入ってくる度に
一瞬 目が入り口に泳ぐ
your eyes immediately
shift to the entrance.
誰かに追われてる証拠だ
This is proof that
you're on the run.
話してくださいよ
Do tell me about it!
俺 そういうのに
すげえ興味あって…
I'm very interested
in such things.
よせよ　考え過ぎだ アホ
That's enough.
You're thinking too much, idiot.
勘ぐるな
Let it go.
気が付かなかった
I didn't realise it.
I see. Did I
really do those things?
そうか　俺は そんな動きを…
恐れてるってことか やつらを…
Am I afraid of them?
Or am I waiting for them?
それとも 待っているのか？
あっ カイジさん　これ…
Kaiji, here.
今 黒ずくめの男が入ってきて
Just now, a guy
wearing black entered.
あの… 携帯の番号っすよね？
かけなくて いいんすか？
Actually, isn't that
a mobile number?
Is it fine not to call?
あっ 俺 トイレ行ってきます
I'm going to the toilet.
誰だ？
ざわ…
Who is it?
名乗れよ　用があるんだろ？
Identify yourself.
What do you want?
I said, who are you?!
名乗れって言って…
This voice is...
この声は…
Kaiji!
カイジさーん
ついてくんな
Don't follow me!
もう 謝ります 謝りますから
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
飲み直しましょうよ
うるせえ
Let's get back
to drinking, alright?
Shut up!
カイジさん？
Kaiji?
遠藤…
Endo.
Congratulations
on surviving, Kaiji.
生還おめでとう　カイジ
送ろう
I'll give you a lift.
待てよ　そう むげにするな
Wait, you don't have
to be so harsh.
お前にとって
実に いい話を持ってきたんだぞ
I have information that
may be good for you.
一晩で
お前の借金が チャラになる
In one night,
you can eliminate your debt.
来週の土曜日 パーティーがある
There will be a party
next Saturday.
今 その参加者を
募っているところだ
Right now, about 60 participants
are being gathered.
60人ばかりな
もちろん ギャンブルだ
Of course, it'll be a gamble.
うまく しのげば 一晩で２千万
いや それ以上の…
If you do well,
you can get 20 million a night.
No, even more than that...
That's enough!
Who would fall for that?!
いいかげんにしろ！
誰がそんな手に…
お願いします！
Please!
僕をそのパーティーに
参加させてください
Please let me join that party!
ば… ばか！
Idiot!
こういうチャンスを
ずっと待ってたんです
This is the chance that
I've been waiting for!
なるほど　やるか？
はい
I see. So, you'll do it?
Yes!
ばか！やめるんだ
Fool, stop it!
This isn't what you think!
これは
お前が考えてるような話じゃねえ
よく知りもしないで…
You can't do it
without knowing more.
分かってるよ
カイジさんの言いたいこと
I understand what
you're trying to say, Kaiji.
リスキーだってことでしょ？
It's risky, isn't it?
でもさ 俺… もう 何ていうか
分かってきちゃったんだよね
But, how do I put it?
I've come to understand...
俺たちみたいな
プーが浮かび上がろうと思ったら
...that if folk like us want
to be able to rise up,
どこかで 一発当てるしかない
...we must somehow
strike it rich all at once.
でなきゃ 風穴なんか開かない
Otherwise, if we can't
open that door,
世間に入っていけないんだって
we won't be able to
move on in this world!
突破口なんだよ これは
佐原…
This is a breakthrough!
Sahara, it's not that I
don't understand how you feel.
その気持ち 分からねえじゃねえ
だったら…
それでも やめろ
In that case...
Even so, you can't!
目を覚ませ
Open your eyes!
こんな うさんくさい男の言うこと
真に受けて 甘い話に浮かれるな
Don't be moved by the glib talk
of this suspicious character!
Kaiji!
カイジさん
いいから待て
Just wait for it!
お前に ふさわしい
本当のチャンスが必ず来る
A decent chance for you
will surely come!
まだ途中なんだよ 俺たち
We're still on the way up...
If we wait a little more,
it will surely...
あと少し待てば 必ず…
来るか そんなもの
As if it would.
何の確証もなく
無責任な きれいごとをよく言うぜ
What an idealistic and
irresponsible thing to say.
一体 何を待つんだ？
What are you waiting for?
Living in a dirty apartment,
薄汚いアパート暮らしをして
貧しいバイト生活しながら
何を待つ？
with a lousy paying job,
what are you waiting for?
You're kidding me.
冗談だろ？
そういうのを無為っていうんだ
That's what they call
"laziness".
くずが…
You're trash.
目を覚まさなきゃならねえのは
お前なんだよ
You're the one who
should open your eyes.
船で お前が作った借金629万
You accumulated a debt of
6.29 million on the ship.
既に 利息込みで668万
With interest,
it's now 6.68 million.
どうやって返すつもりだ？
How do you intend
to repay that?
どうやってって…
How...?
言っとくがな
今 はやりの自己破産
Let me tell you, the trend of
declaring yourself a bankrupt...
...and submitting an
application to the court...
支払い不能を裁判所に申し立てて
借金をチャラにする…
...so that you don't need
to repay, won't work.
免責っていう手は 利かねえぞ
お前の借金は ギャンブルの負け
Your debt is the result
of losing a gamble.
The law does not protect
what is obviously a problem...
そういう 明らかに
本人の生活態度に問題がある場合
法的な保護は されない
...due to your own lifestyle.
免責は下りないってわけだ
They will not grant you
such an exemption.
In the first place,
even if you got an exemption,
もっとも 仮に免責が下りても
俺たちは取り立てるがな
we'd still come to
collect what's ours.
どうする？どうやって返す？
Well? How will you repay?
働くさ
フフフ… 分かってねえなあ
I'll work!
You don't get it, do you?
Your debt of nearly 7 million...
この700万近い借金
もう 働いて返すレベルじゃねえ
...is no longer an amount
you can work to repay.
計算したことあるのか？
Have you ever done
any calculation?
How much is your hourly wage?
お前らの時給は いくらだ？
900円です
900 yen an hour.
１日９時間
Assuming you work 26 days
a month for 9 hours a day,
仮に26日働いて 月給21万
your monthly wage
is 210,000 yen.
If you give 100,000 every month
to repay your debt,
借金返済に
毎月10万 返したとして…
どれぐらいかかると思う？
how long do you
think you'll need?
どれぐらいって…
How long?
197ヵ月
197 months.
つまり 16年と５ヵ月
In other words,
16 years and 5 months.
返済が終わるのは
お前が40近くなったころ
By the time you finish repaying,
you'll be nearly 40.
お前 そこまで待つつもりかよ？
Do you intend
to wait until then?
カイジ…
この手は何のためについてる？
Kaiji!
What are these
hands of yours for?
これまでの人生で
何かを築いた者にとっては
To someone who has built up
something in his life,
それを放さないため
守るためにある
it's so that he won't let it go,
and to protect it.
だが 持たざる者が それでは
話にならない
But for those who simply wait,
these words mean nothing.
お前たちは その手で
つかみに行かなきゃ駄目なんだ
You must grab it with those
hands of yours and move on!
でなきゃ 道は開けない
If not, the path
will not be opened!
ざわ… ざわ…
２千万　これが 一晩だ
20 million in one night.
この金が
お前を解放し 未来へ導く
That money will set you free
and pave your future.
この救いを見逃すのか？
Will you let your chance
to be saved slip by?
何をちゅうちょする？つかめ！
Why do you hesitate?
Seize it! Release those
fear-filled arms,
臆病に組んだ腕を解き…
つかむんだ！
and seize it!
No need to hesitate!
迷うことはない！
この金は お前の未来そのものだ
Your future depends on
that money!
俺が救いの光… 星のもとへ
お前を連れてってやる
I'm the saving light who
directs you to the stars!
But before that, whether
you can hold on to the stars...
ただ そこから先…
星をつかむか否かは お前個人の力
...depends on
your individual strength.
時間と集合場所だ
This is the time
and meeting place.
お願いします
Thank you.
何を待つつもりだ？
この救いを見逃すのか？
What are you waiting for?
Will you let your chance
to be saved slip by?!
迷うことはない！つかむんだ！
No need to hesitate!
Seize it!
遠藤の言うとおり カイジには
Like what Endo said,
Kaiji has no strategy to
break out of his current debts.
今の圧倒的 閉塞状態を
打ち破る策など何一つない
遠藤の持ってきた この話は
Endo's proposal
is like a rescue ship,
いわば
この絶望的日々に溺れかけた
that came to save Kaiji
from drowning...
カイジの前に現れた救助の船
...in such a hopeless situation.
まさしく 救いの光
It's like
the light of salvation.
What lies in
Kaiji's heart now...
今 カイジの中にあるのは
迷いでも
自分を抑える理性の言葉でもない
...is neither hesitation
nor self-restraint.
たった一つ 突き上げてくる思い
Only one thought comes
straight to his mind.
This time, I will not blunder!
今度こそ… しくじるものか
時　７月13日 午後９時
The date and time is
13th of July, 9pm.
New Central Keiyou,
Starside Hotel.
京葉新都心 スターサイドホテル
[Come to where the stars are]
来たれ 星のもとへ！
Come to where the stars are!
来たれ 星のもとへ
I was told to...
あっ 俺 今日…
カイジは 再び足を踏み出した
Once again, Kaiji steps forward.
星の光など届くはずもない
ギャンブルという 漆黒の闇の中へ
Towards the pitch-black
darkness known as gambling,
where the light of stars
never reach.
闇の中へ…
Into the darkness!
Next, Revelry.